创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
火星 与战神同名
Mars--the god of war's brooding namesake...
一直以来
has long held sway...
让地球的后裔为之倾倒
over the hearts and dreams of the scions of Earth.
将来 机器人探索者将会取代载人航天任务
In the future, robotic rovers will be replaced by manned missions.
但是首批人类探险家将是开路先锋
But the first human explorers will just be blazing the trail...
以建立永久定居点 火星大都市
for a permanent settlement, a Martian metropolis.
科学家和工程师已经在设计我们将来
Scientists and engineers are already designing...
在这个空间殖民地生存的所需的一切
everything we'll need to survive in this space colony of the future.
这是我们在另一个星球上旅行的唯一办法
This is the only way to ride on another planet.
尽管有了尖端的科技 定居在这个外星世界里
Despite cutting-edge technology, living full-time on this alien world...
将会是一场为了生存的严酷斗争
will be a relentless battle for survival.
我们将直面致我们于死地的环境
We're going to be staring out at an environment...that's lethal to us.
所有的科技 危险 疑惑都来自
These are the technologies, the dangers, and the wonders...
《太空生活》
of "Living in Space."
宇宙:太空生活
23世纪初
It's the dawn of the 23rd century...
人类已经在火星上建立了成熟的殖民地
and man has established a full-fledged colony on Mars.
这并不容易
It hasn't been easy.
在火星上 我们是入侵者
On Mars, we are the invaders...
愤怒的红色星球已经向我们开战
and the angry red planet has declared war on us...
利用其本性
using its very nature--
炙热的辐射 稀薄的空气 致命的沙尘暴
scorching radiation, razor-thin air, and lethal dust storms--
确保生命在这里将陷入一场持久战
to ensure life here will be a constant struggle.
那么何苦要生活在太空呢?
So why bother to live in space at all?
为何这些勇敢的开拓者
Why did these brave pioneers...
就不能挤在安全的陆地上呢?
not simply stay huddled together where it is safe...on terra firma?
我们至少应该是两星物种
We should be at least a two-planet species.
换句话说 将所有的鸡蛋放在一个篮子里
In other words, it's simply too dangerous...
太危险了
to put all our eggs in one basket.
火星是我们最近的邻居
Mars is our closest neighbor.
它不管好歹
It's the one that's, for better or worse...
最类似于我们亲爱的地球
most similar to our beloved Earth.
它是最具潜力的星球
And it's the one that has the most possibilities.
不光是昼夜25小时
It's not just the 25-hour days...
还有类似的季节轮换
and the similar composition of seasons...
让太阳的第四颗行星成为了人类
that made the fourth planet from the Sun the ultimate destination...
在宇宙间安第二个家的最终目的地
for mankind's second home in the cosmos.
尤其是有一种资源
There is one resource in particular...
让火星成为了
that clinched Mars as the runaway favorite...
我们未来殖民地的喜出望外的宠儿
for our colony of the future.
我们宇航员的最重要的任务之一就是获取能源
One of the first missions for our astronauts is to get energy.
能源之一
And one form of energy...
实际上就在他们脚下的冻土里
is actually underneath their feet in the permafrost.
就在火星的地表下 存在着固态水
Right into the ground of Mars there is frozen water.
我们可以净化饮用
We can purify it for drinking purposes.
同样 我们可以分解出氧和氢
Also, we can separate out the oxygen and the hydrogen...
来充当火箭燃料 来打造燃料电池
to create rocket fuel in order to create fuel cells...
来为火星殖民地提供能量
which will then energize our colony on Mars.
殖民地本身就是个工程奇迹
The colony itself is an engineering marvel.
虽然没几个方案
While there were a few scenarios considered...
考虑了兴建永久火星定居点
for constructing a permanent Martian settlement...
包括地下居住点
including an underground habitat...
但是还是最熟悉老套的
it was the most familiar and timeworn...
被选作23世纪的殖民地
that was chosen for the 23rd-century colony.
穹顶是极端环境中的理想结构
Domes are ideal structures for extreme environments...
比方说沙漠 尤其是火星
say, the desert, or particularly Mars...
原因就在于
and the reason is the dome creates...
穹顶能够用最少的结构和材料
the largest environment, enclosed space...
创造出最大的环境 封闭的空间
with a minimum amount of structure and mass...
那是非常重要的
which is very important.
同时它们也非常的坚固
Also they're very, very strong.
基地宛如一个大都市
The base is more like a metropolis...
有一系列的小穹顶
a series of smaller domes...
从一个中心控制枢纽依次展开
rotating out from one central dominant hub...
如车轮上的辐条一般
like the spokes on a wagon wheel.
我喜欢一个大穹顶的想法
I love the idea of one large dome...
它作为中央广场位于中央
being the central plaza, the central place...
四周是小穹顶
the place to be at, surrounded by smaller domes.
火星沙漠中央的这种高科技绿洲
This high-tech oasis in the middle of the Martian desert...
建造得像一座城堡
is built like a fortress.
我们所使用的材料必须能承受严寒
The material we use has to be able to withstand the cold...
还有辐射
and also the radiation.
火星表面经过了荒漠化
The surface of Mars gets sterilized...
经过了严酷的阳光的漂白
bleached by harsh sunlight...
那是因为火星没有臭氧保护层
because Mars has no protective ozone layer.
某种玻璃纤维和树脂材料
Certain kinds of fiberglass and Plexiglas materials...
必须要进行加强
would have to be reinforced...
把钢筋放到玻璃里
reinforcement bars placed within the glass...
这样获得的结构 在结构上坚固得足以
in order to get a structure that is structurally strong enough...
承受巨大的压力
to withstand the enormous strains...
以及红色星球上的巨大的温差
and plunging temperatures on the Red Planet.
穹顶里的温度和气压
Temperature and pressure within the dome...
必须严格控制
have to be strictly regulated.
如果温度太高
If it gets too warm...
定居点里膨胀的气压
the expanding air pressure within the habitat...
将会导致其爆炸 就像是过度膨胀的热气球
will cause it to explode like an over-inflated hot air balloon.
然而到此为止 穹顶已经履行了自己的职责
But so far, the dome has done its job of protecting...
来保护日益增多的地球开拓者
the ever-expanding band of pioneering earthlings.
尽管有大规模的穹顶
Despite the grand scale of the dome...
但是我们的移民每天早晨醒来
our colonists awake each morning...
所面对的显然是相当艰苦的
to accommodations that are decidedly Spartan.
居住在火星上其实是很紧张的
The life on Mars is actually very stressful.
居住点很狭窄 很简陋
The living quarters are very small and very stark.
但是想象一下 你要是在那里住上几年
But imagine if you're living that way for years.
非常孤单 完全不同于地球
It's very claustrophobic, and it's very foreign from Earth.
你完全接触不到草地 树木 天空
You've lost touch with the grass and the trees and the sky.
不过换来的却是引人入胜的
But the tradeoff is spectacular--
有机会生活在红色的苍穹之下
the chance to live under a crimson sky.
火星距离太阳约1.5个天文单位(1天文单位=日地距离)
Mars is about one and a half astronomical units out from the sun.
地球是一个天文单位 因此它还要远出一半
The Earth is one, so it's half again as far.
你所处地方更加昏暗
It's dimmer when you get there...
火星上的天空不是蓝天
and the sky on Mars is not so blue.
其之所以是红色 原因就在氧化物尘埃就在头顶
It's red because all of this oxidized dust that's aloft...
狂风始终吹个不停
and these winds blowing all the time.
为了让这个外星世界感觉更像故乡
To make this alien world feel more like home...
我们的游客带来了自己的人工生态系统
our travelers have brought with them artificial ecosystems.
不过植物在那里并非是为了享受
But the plants aren't there purely for comfort.
它们提供了至关重要的作用
They serve a vital function in creating and sustaining...
以打造与维持栖息地的封闭环境
a closed environment for the habitat.
我们要在火星上种植的岂止是粮食
We're going to be growing more than food on Mars.
我们需要从植物获得氧气
We are getting the oxygen we need from the plants...
而植物则需要获得所需的二氧化碳
the plants will be getting the carbon dioxide they need.
那就是人与植物之间的和谐关系
It's a beautiful synergy between humans and plants in that regard.
那种共生关系
That symbiotic relationship...
反映在火星生活的方方面面
is reflected in every aspect of life on Mars.
类似于地球上的水族馆
Like an aquarium on Earth...
所有的资源都会被循环利用 没有浪费
every resource is recycled, nothing is wasted.
我们可以来看一下水族馆里生长着鱼类和藻类
We can think of an aquarium with fish and algae growing in it.
如果你将它封闭起来
And if you could seal that off...
可以有一个理想的食物 垃圾的循环
you could get a nice food/waste cycle...
变废为宝
converting wastes to renewable resources.
那就是二氧化碳和氧气的关系
That's what carbon dioxide and oxygen are.
还有养分
And also the nutrition.
鱼吃藻类 排泄出固体垃圾
The fish eat the algae, they excrete solid wastes...
降解了水中的细菌
and these degrade from bacteria in the water...
那又成为了藻类攫取的养分
and those become nutrients for the algae to take up again.
不同于水族馆的是
Unlike an aquarium...
我们无法源源不断地
we're not going to be able to keep importing...
补充新鲜的海水和空气
fresh supplies of seawater, fresh supplies of air.
我们定居空间的子孙
Our space-dwelling descendants...
将必须掌握
are going to have to have mastered the art...
自给自足环境中的艺术
of self-contained environments...
生态维生循环 循环利用所有的水
ecological life-support cycles that recycle all the water...
循环利用所有的空气
recycle all the air.
如果他们运用自如
If they do it well...
他们就应该如鱼缸里的鱼儿那样欢快
they should be just as happy as the fish in a tank.
然而在20世纪
But in the 20th century...
尚没有完全了解人类在这样闭合的系统里
it wasn't well understood how happy humans would be...
在这个与世隔绝的世界里如何获得幸福
in such a closed-loop system, sealed off from the outside world.
想法就是在
The concept was put to the test...
所谓的生物圈2号的设施里进行实验
in a facility called Biosphere 2.
其最初的目的 尤其是
Its original purpose, among other things...
作为在另一个星球上
was as a trial run...
建立自给自足殖民地的试验
for a self-sustaining colony on another planet.
生物圈2号是一个巨大的环境控制设施
Biosphere 2 is a large, environmentally controlled facility...
可以与外部环境完全封闭和隔离
that can be completely closed and sealed from the outside environment...
里面的环境可以完全操控
and the inside environment can be completely manipulated...
这样不同的气候条件和不同的生态区
so that different climate regimes and different biomes...
可以在设施里面进行调控
can be controlled within the facility.
生物圈2号集中了5个不同的生态系统或生态区
Biosphere 2 is a collection of five different ecosystems, or biomes...
每一个都采集自地球不同的角落
each gathered from a different corner of the Earth.
它们包括沙漠
They include a desert...
湿地
wetlands...
草原
savanna grasslands...
热带雨林
a tropical rainforest...
甚至还有一个迷你海洋
and even a miniature ocean.
这个雄心勃勃的项目投入了实验
This ambitious project was put to the test...
是在1991年进行了它首次封闭任务
with its first sealed mission in 1991.
但是很快就遇到了严重的问题
But it soon ran into serious problems.
一度 参试人员开始表现出不计后果 丧失判断力
At one point, the crew began exhibiting recklessly impaired judgment...
甚至分裂 相互仇视
and even split into rival factions.
整个任务岌岌可危
The entire mission was in jeopardy...
直到发现是缺氧
until it was discovered that a lack of oxygen...
触发了组员们的好斗行为
was the trigger for the crew's belligerent behavior.
最终追溯到了一个看似微不足道的细节
It was eventually traced back to a seemingly insignificant detail.
结构里面的水泥没有得到适当的凝固
The cement inside the structure hadn't been allowed to cure properly.
其结果就是 水泥结构所吸收的氧气
As a result, the cement structure was absorbing far more oxygen...
超过了植物的补充
than the plants could replenish.
呼吸用气的降低所达到的水平
This drawdown of breathable air...
相当于海拔1.8万英尺
reached levels equivalent to those found...at an altitude of 18,000 feet.
其效果类似于登山者在致命高度的遭遇
Similar effects are endured by mountain climbers at lethal heights.
最终 清新的空气不得不注入生物圈
Eventually, fresh air had to be injected into Biosphere.
这样的救援是不可能用于我们勇敢的火星殖民地
No such aid is available for our intrepid Martian colony...
在那里诸如水泥未能固化的小疏忽
where a small oversight like failing to cure cement...
将被证明是致命的
would prove fatal.
尽管具有内在的危险
Despite its inherent dangers...
穹顶里封闭的环境依然是火星上最安全的地方
the closed environment of the dome is the safest place to be on Mars.
但是有时移民必须要离开这个舒适的区域
But sometimes the colonists must leave this comfort zone...
到户外去
and step outside.
随着太阳在火星上升起
As the Sun rises over Mars...
一些移民要走出穹顶
a few colonists strike out from the dome...
去完成当天的研究和维护任务
to fulfill their research assignments and maintenance duties for the day.
他们的班车将带他们穿越红色星球
Their commute will take them...
锈色斑斑的荒芜旷野
across the empty, rusted plains of the Red Planet.
为了高效完成任务
In order to accomplish this mission efficiently...
居民们需要选择可以徒步穿越的地形
the inhabitants need an alternative to crossing the terrain on foot.
我们一旦登陆火星
When we go to Mars...
真的对这个星球了解不多
we really don't know that much about the planet...
如果我们只登陆在一个地方
and if we just land in one place...
我们将会对该地方了解很多
we're going to learn a lot about that one place...
而有可能对这个星球了解甚少
but maybe not a lot about the planet.
因此我们肯定需要
So we definitely need the ability to have mobility...
能够迁徙和长途跋涉
and go long distances.
这台阿波罗登月任务所用的月球车
The rover used for this purpose on the Apollo Moon mission...
是一辆敞篷车 基本上就是放大版的沙地车
was a convertible, essentially just an amped-up dune buggy.
这辆月球车出色地完成了自己的任务
The lunar rover served its purpose beautifully.
它使得两名探险者
It allowed the two human explorers...
无需费力的徒步
to not get too fatigued walking around...
而是带着他们漫游在月球表面
but instead allowed them to rove around the lunar surface...
探索更大的范围
and explore out to a greater range.
不过同时 这显然是短距离
But at the same time, this was clearly...
短期任务的解决方案
a short-range, short-duration mission solution.
但是火星上的地产要来得多得多
But there's much more real estate to cover on Mars.
来见识一下战车吧
Meet the Chariot...
这最先进的模型
the most advanced model to emerge from the minds...
源自航天局21世纪工程师的智慧
of NASA's 21st century engineers.
除了镀金和儒勒.凡尔纳的外表
In addition to the gold plating and Jules Verne look...
这台太空车具有某些特色
this space truck has some features...
让外太空里的巡航活动事倍功半
that streamline the cruising experience in outer space.
每一个车轮都可以旋转360度
Each one of the wheels can rotate 360 degrees...
因此我们就能够驾驭自如
so we can actually drive it perfectly...
侧移 前进 任意方向
sideways or forward or in any direction.
这种灵活性意味着
This versatility means that it can conquer...
它可以征服多数行星地形
most interplanetary topography...
还不止这些
and that's not all.
宇航服在中间不能很好地弯曲
Spacesuits don't bend very well in the middle.
因此即使我们考虑座位
So even though we think of seats...
直接采用满街跑的汽车那样的方法
as the obvious way to ride a car around town...
其实那是没有任何意义的
it really doesn't make sense.
这里我们安装了这个垂直的连接体
So we built this upright interface.
这里有个环 宇航服就嵌入在里面
There's a ring here where the suit plugs in.
宇航服所有的重量靠这个垂直的塔台来支撑
All the weight of the suit is taken by this upright turret.
这是在其它星球上驾车的唯一办法
This is the only way to ride on another planet.
火星虽然是颗大行星
Mars, though, is a vast planet...
但要搜索更偏僻的角落
and to search its more distant corners...
我们殖民地科学家的驰骋需要别具一格
our colony's scientists need to ride in style.
他们宁愿穿着连衣裤工作
They prefer to work in jumpsuits...
而不是几个小时连续呆在笨重的宇航服里
rather than having to remain in an unwieldy spacesuit for hours on end.
唯一的可能就是他们能够保持一个环境
This is only possible if they can maintain an environment...
其大气压相当于老家地球上的情况
with atmospheric pressure akin to that found on the home world, Earth.
那里是小型充压漫游车所到之处
That's where the Small Pressurized Rover comes in.
我会说它就像是宇航服和跑车的组合
I would call it sort of a combination of a spacesuit and a sports car.
它是运动型探险车
It's a sporty rover.
它具有非凡的机动性
It's got great maneuverability.
战车的底盘
The chassis of the Chariot...
实际上构成了小型充压漫游车的基座
actually forms the base of the Small Pressurized Rover.
小型充压漫游车的驾驶舱
The cabin on the Small Pressurized Rover...
是从这里一直延伸到这里
would start about here and run all the way back to about here...
一直到车子的屁股
leaving the rear of the vehicle...
有点像卡车的底盘
kind of like the bed of a pickup truck...
这样就可以携带更多的荷载
so that's available for carrying additional payloads.
我们可以升起那机器
We can upgrade the machine...
在野外将其变成各种设备
and turn it into all kinds of pieces of equipment out in the field.
在车尾
On the rear of the vehicle...
我们可以插入各种工具
we can plug a number of different implements...
比如说推土机的叶片
for example, bulldozer blades...
就是一些实用的东西 如绞车 反铲挖土机和其它工具
just something practical like a winch, backhoes, and other tools.
小型充压漫游车(SPR)
The Small Pressurized Rover, or SPR...
比阿波罗登月车稍大一些
is only slightly bigger than the Apollo rover.
其最高时速约6英里
It has a top speed of about six miles per hour.
SPR在任务中的使用
The SPR can be deployed for missions...
可以从3天持续到两个礼拜
lasting from three days up to two weeks...
其覆盖的范围超过500英里
and covering distances of over 500 miles.
某些优化也使得它
Certain enhancements also make it...
成为了宇航员的首选交通工具
the spaceman's transportation of choice.
两件宇航服
A pair of spacesuits hangs on the exterior...
挂在小型充压漫游车外
of the Small Pressurized Rover.
在增压车内的乘客
The passengers in the pressurized interior of the vehicle...
可以经过后舱门进入宇航服
can enter the suits through a rear hatch...
在星球表面
and be walking along the planetary surface...
行走上短短的10分钟
in as little as ten minutes.
航天局艾姆斯研究中心的科学家李天龙博士
A scientist with the NASA Ames Research Center, Dr. Pascal Lee...
在探索另一辆汽车 那是个原型
explores another vehicle that is a precursor...
专门用于火星的车子
to one being designed for Mars.
他联手Nick Baggarly
He joined forces with Nick Baggarly...
他是《环球驾驶》的执行董事
executive director of Drive Around the World...
那是个旅游探险组织
a travel adventure organization.
这样的车子十分出色
Vehicles like this are fantastic...
因为你可以用它来模拟
because you can use them for analogs...
佯装你在另一个星球上旅行和越野
for pretending like you're traveling or traversing on another planet.
我们打造它以便去任何地方
So we built it so it could kind of go anywhere.
这辆车子正准备去探险格林兰
This is a vehicle that's being prepared for an expedition to Greenland...
随后会去南极
and then later on to the South Pole.
你可以看到这里有个房间
You can see here that there's going to be room...
虽然不大
not much though, but room...
但是这房间会有所有的设备和补给
for all of the equipment and supplies...
那都是你探索月球和火星所必需的
that you will need to explore the Moon and Mars.
不过它给了航天局的工程师和科学家们
But it's giving engineers and scientists at NASA...
一些真实的第一手想法 就是如何来设计
some real firsthand ideas about how to design a pressurized rover...
探索火星的充压漫游车
for exploring Mars.
这种设计粗犷的车子有一组独特的车轮
This robustly designed vehicle has a unique set of wheels.
履带用上这组轮子
The tracks use this set of road wheels...
但是实际上是这个滚动轮在驱动履带
but this round hamster wheel is what actually drives the track.
它旋转 连接到车子的主轴
It spins around, connected to the spindle of the vehicle...
推动这些橡胶凸出体来驱动履带
and pushes on these rubber lugs to propel the track.
每一节有3英尺长 16英寸宽
Each one measures 3 feet long by 16 inches wide...
在路面上的橡胶超过了500平方英寸
which is over 500 square inches of rubber on the road.
因为每一条履带都有一个内置的悬挂系统
Because each track has a built-in suspension system...
实际上可以和它所处的
it can actually articulate and follow the curve...
地形紧密接触
of the terrain that it's on.
因此这整个装置是可以转动的
So this entire apparatus can pivot...
因此要是你要越过一块巨石
so if you're going over a boulder...
履带实际上就会在巨石下面站起来
the track will actually get up underneath the boulder...
然后就是爬过去
and then just crawl up and over it.
火星是颗沙质星球
Mars is a gritty planet.
尘埃泥土会无孔不入
Dirt, dust, and grime get into everything.
尤其是对有着运动机件的轮式车辆
This is especially true of a wheeled vehicle with moving parts...
机械系统很容易遭到腐蚀
where the mechanisms can easily be corroded.
危险就在于履带空转
The danger is having a track over-rotate...
一旦发生这种情况
and when it does...
你就靠双手在野外修理了
you have a field repair situation on your hands.
途中修车还算不幸中的大幸
Fixing a vehicle on the road is risky under the best circumstances...
但是在外太空 容不得丝毫错误
but in outer space, there is zero margin for error.
如果你发生故障或遇上任何麻烦
And if you break down or get into any kind of trouble...
援助是鞭长莫及的
help is a long way away, if it can reach you at all.
对此你要意识到 要是你无法在户外呼吸
You realize that at that point, if you couldn't breathe outside...
要是你无法置身于车子外面
if you couldn't just step outside of your vehicle...
而要开始进行作业
and somehow start working on it...
你就有可能眼睁睁看着自己呼出你最后一口气
you might be just watching yourself breathe your last breaths of air...
因为你的生命维持系统
as your life-support system allows you to survive...
此时会让你存活上几个小时
a few hours at that spot...
但是这里将是你葬身之地
but this is where you're going to die.
幸好 航天局的应变计划已经酝酿了
Fortunately, NASA has a contingency plan in mind.
小型充压漫游车的一个很好的优势
One of the nice advantages of the Small Pressurized Rovers...
就在于 由于它们相对小而轻巧
is that, because they're relatively small and light...
我们实际上可以投入两辆
we can actually launch two.
这样我们安排上两辆组成的系统
So we operate with a system of two together...
就好像伙伴系统
sort of like a buddy system...
每一辆漫游车里有两名宇航员
where there's two astronauts in each rover...
出去远行
and they go out long ranges.
一旦其中之一发生故障
And if one of them should break down...
那么所有四名宇航员就可以搭乘另一辆车回家
then all four astronauts can get in the other one and come home.
至于这些红色星球改装车的价格...
As for the price tag of one of these Red Planet hot rods...
人们也问过我其成本有多少
People also ask me how much it costs...
我只能说其成本大于法拉利
and I can only say that it costs more than a Ferrari.
移民不只是驰骋在火星地貌上别具一格
Colonists are not only racing the Martian landscape in style...
他们还会炫耀尖端设计的太空外套
they'll be sporting a cutting-edge design in space outerwear...
看上去很酷 就像是超级英雄的穿戴
that looks remarkably like a superhero's.
作为他们日常研究任务之一
As one of their daily researuh assignments...
我们未来的火星移民
our Martian colonists of the future...
将探索太阳系里最大的火山 奥林帕斯山
explore the largest volcano in the solar system, Olympus Mons.
但是即使是执行日常琐事
But even while performing routine chores...
火星也潜伏着捕杀任何入侵者
Mars is waiting to ambush and kill any intruder.
层层保护是地球人永恒的需求
Layers of protection are a constant requirement for Earthlings.
一旦离开了安全的穹顶
When not in the safety of the dome...
移民们必须置身于加压漫游车里
colonists must be in a pressurized rover...
或受囿于宇航服
or in the crushing confines of their spacesuits.
完成了四次太空行走
Having done four spacewalks...
在宇航服里度过了一昼夜
and spent over a 24-hour period in spacesuits...
这服装实在是和你过不去
the suits are hard on you.
它们僵硬死板
They're stiff as a board, and they're pressurized...
其加压如足球的压力
to the same pressure as a football.
约每平方英寸4.3磅
It's like 4.3 pounds per square inch.
因此你每次都要握紧双手 活动手套
So every time you go to close your hands and move your gloves...
要对付膨胀的压力
you're working against that inflation pressure...
那是非常劳累的
and it can be very fatiguing.
宇航服会造成指甲或其它的伤害
It can cause fingernail damage and other trauma from the suits.
宇航服必须保护里面脆弱的人类
A spacesuit must defend the fragile human inside...
免遭外太空的各种威胁
from the numerous threats of outer space.
我们需要对其加压 需要对其供氧
We need to pressurize them, we need to give them oxygen...
我们要控制其温度和湿度
we want to control for temperature and humidity...
因而我们在宇航服设计中考虑了这一切
so we do all of that within a spacesuit design.
它必须满足人类的需求
While it must accommodate human needs...
但同时宇航服也必须是牢固的保护盾
a spacesuit must also be a constant shield...
以对付无情的宇宙
against an unforgiving universe.
火星武库里一件致命的武器
One lethal weapon in Mars' arsenal...
是司空见惯的微流星雨
is a commonly occurring micro-meteor shower...
闪闪发光的微流星体
emitting tiny meteors...
其中任何一颗都足以击穿宇航服
any one of which is enough to puncture a suit...
造成可怕的伤亡
leading to a gruesome death.
多层氯丁橡胶和凯夫拉构成的绝缘体
Insulation with layers of neoprene and Kevlar...
决定着保证宇航员的安全
is critical to keeping the astronaut safe...
免遭凶险星球的各种不测
from every encounter with a treacherous planet.
携带维生系统导致了宇航服
Carrying a life-support system results in a suit...
异常笨重 穿戴繁琐
that is so bulky and cumbersome to wear...
要化上3个小时
it can take up to three hours...
才能让国际空间站的宇航员
for an astronaut on the International Space Station...
穿上MMU 人控机动单元
to don an MMU, or Manned Maneuverable Unit.
其中包括了30分钟的预呼吸
That includes 30 minutes of pre-breathing...
宇航员要吸入的纯氧
the pure oxygen atmosphere that the astronaut will be inhaling.
不过在麻省理工 科学家正利用机器人
But at MIT, scientists are using robotics...
来帮助打造新的更加精简的宇航服
to help create a new, more streamlined spacesuit...
它直接来自连环画册
straight out of the pages of a comic book.
宇航服的未来就是活动
The future of spacesuits is all about locomotion...
机动性和灵活性
and mobility and dexterity.
因此我们需要截然不同的设计
So we needed a completely different design...
几乎是对当今宇航服的革命性的设计
pretty much a revolutionary uesign from current suits today.
一旦我们穿上生物服去探索火星
When we explore on Mars in a Bio-Suit...
我们就会如极限运动员那样
we're going to be like an extreme athlete.
我们去火星探索的理由
The reason we're going to Mars to explore...
就是去搜寻过去生命的证据
is to search for the evidence of past life.
因此我们在火星上 需要弯腰
So on Mars, we need to bend down...
寻找化石 寻找生命
and look for fossils, look for life.
因此生物服的主要设计原则
So the primary design principle of the Bio-Suit...
就是赋予宇航员最大的机动性
is to afford the astronauts maximum mobility...
并保持最小的能量消耗
while maintaining a minimum energy consumption.
这只是个机械系统
This is just a mechanical system...
但是设想一下
but imagine that this wire...
这条线是用记忆合金制造的
was made out of a shape-memory alloy.
你可以看到 随着我将它卷起 这线就会收进去
So you can see, as l twist this up, the wire comes in...
就收紧了我身上的衣服
and it tightens up the suit around me.
就是说我们将压力直接施加给皮肤
What that means is we're applying the pressure directly to the skin.
这也就是我们将它称为第二层皮服装的原因所在
That's also why we call it a second-skin suit.
生物服的维生系统是模块化的
The life support system for the Bio-Suit is modular...
使其舒适度远远超过目前笨重的宇航服
making it much more comfortable than the current unwieldy spacesuit.
坚硬的躯壳连接到背包
A hard torso shell connects to the backpack...
里面装有维生系统
that contains the life-support system.
头盔面罩会镀上黄金
The helmet visor will be painted gold...
和现代宇航服一样
like contemporary spacesuits...
目的是为了抵御致盲的阳光
in order to defend against the blinding illumination of the sun.
头盔里还装有抬头显示器(HUD)
The helmet will also contain a heads-up display, or HUD...
可以将重要的信息传递给探险者
that can relay vital information to the explorer.
我们设想宇航员透过自己的头盔
We envision the astronaut looks through their helmet...
看到显示 自己的生理显示
and they'll see the displays, their physiological displays--
心率 血压
heart rate, blood pressure--
而且还有他们所需的所有的导航信息
but also all the navigation information that they need...
即三维地形图
so a 3-D topographical map.
一般来说 设计师只在乎宇航服的
Normally, designers only worry about spacesuits...
安全和功能
being safe and functional.
然而生物服的发明者也希望能确保
But the Bio-Suit inventors also wanted to make sure...
自己的作品美观大方
that their creation was aesthetically pleasing.
我们希望生物服
We hope that the Bio-Suit...
看上去漂亮精美
looks really beautiful and wonderful.
它并不是刻意要做的看上去像蜘蛛人服装
It wasn't intentionally made to look like a Spider-Man suit.
生物服只是一个超前的科技
The Bio-Suit is just one futuristic technology...
可能有朝一日成为火星移民的外表
that may someday make an appearance in the Martian colony.
但是无论你穿戴何种宇航服
But no matter what spacesuit you're wearing...
漫步火星将永远不会是在公园里溜达
a stroll on Mars will never be a walk in the park.
火星移民可以穿戴得像超级英雄
Martian colonists may dress like superheroes...
但是他们不是万能的
but they aren't all-powerful.
有时他们需要依靠机器人搭档
Sometimes they need to rely on a robotic sidekick:
机器太空人
The Robonaut.
机器太空人是机器人宇航员助理
Robonaut is a robotic astronaut assistant.
在这个特定的情况下
In this particular case...
它是一台较低身段的全地形漫游者
it has an all-terrain-tupe rover for a lower body.
这是我们对古希腊神话里的人头马的诠释
It's our interpretation of the ancient Greek myths...of a horse with a human body on top.
机器太空人项目将人类的聪明才智
The Robonaut project fuses human ingenuity...
与机械力量柔和在一起
with mechanical muscle...
借助于其远程操控系统
through its telepresence operating system.
你可以将它看作是非常先进的操控模式
You can think of it as a very advanced puppeteer mode...
你戴上一套现实虚拟装备
where you put on a set of virtual reality gear...
直接来控制机器人
and then control the robot directly.
他的活动可以转换成机器人的活动
His motions get translated into robot motions.
液晶头盔上有两个显示屏
An LCD helmet with two screens...
直接映射出机器人头上的两个摄像机
map directly to the two cameras in the robot's head...
在该模式下 我们可以以非常自然的方式
and in that mode, we can perform a lot of tasks...
来执行很多任务
in a very natural way.
摄像机受到头盔的保护
The cameras are protected by a helmet...
是模仿古罗马的百夫长的盔甲
modeled after Roman centurion armor.
机器人也可以以自主模式来操控
The robot can also operate in an autonomous mode...
它利用自己的人工智能
where it employs its own artificial intelligence...
来执行预编程的任务
to carry out pre-programmed assignments.
由于它开拓的道路是人们涉足有所顾虑的
Since it will be blazing trails where people dread to set foot...
因此机器太空人的大小和形状是至关重要的
Robonauts' size and shape are crucial.
机器太空人旨在帮助人类完成人类的工作
Robonaut is designed to help humans do human tasks...
因此人类的形状是达到目标的自然而然的方式
so the human form is a natural way to achieve that goal.
如果你欲使用同样的工具
If you want to be able to work with the same tools...
在同样的环境下工作
work in the same environment...
拥有大小大致相同的肢体肯定是有好处的
having roughly the same size appendages certainly helps.
其中一个例子就是利用机器太空人
One example of this is using Robonaut...
来接手运行殖民地固有的更多的日常事务
to take over the more routine tasks inherent to running the colony.
机器人担纲的最佳角色就是让机器人来履行
The best role to give robots is to have the robots cover...
人类去做太危险的事情
what is either too dangerous for humans to do...
以及机器人会做得更好的事情
or things that are simply better done by robots.
但是机器太空人不仅仅是个技术员
But the Robonaut is not merely a technician.
它的才干是完成任务的关键
His talents are critical to the success of the mission.
另一项我们对机器人寄予厚望的
Another very important role that we are seeing for robots...
就是走出去侦查险情
is to go out there and scout for dangers...
还有确实需要深入探索的有趣的科学地点
but also for interesting scientific sites to really explore in-depth.
机器人还是非常合适的侦查工具
The robots are still very convenient tools for reconnaissance.
与漫游车一样 机器太空人的动力来自太阳能
Like the rover, the Robonaut runs on a solar-powered...
锂离子电池
lithium-lon battery.
虽然给机器充电是一项简单的任务
While charging the machine is a simple task...
但是为人类居民提供能量远不是简单的事情
fueling the human settlers is not nearly as straightforward.
挨饿将会是笼罩移民的持续阴影
Starvation will be a constant shadow looming over the colonists...
假如不稳定的平衡得不到持续的话
and if a precarious balance is not maintained...
末日终将来临
the end is always near.
对于我们未来的无畏的火星移民来说
For our fearless Mars colonists of the future...
满足哪怕最原始的需求
satisfying even the most primal needs...
都证明是艰巨的挑战
proves to be a daunting hardship.
所要对付的有可能是最基本的需求 食物
Take what may be the most basic need of all--food.
约需花费每磅14万美元才能将东西
It costs about $140,000 a pound to transport anything...
从地球送往火星
from Earth's surface to Mars' surface.
可以是食物 可以是水 可以是空气
That can be food, it can be water, it can be air.
因此 考虑到花费高昂的成本
So, given the prohibitive cost...
来进口几吨包装食品
of importing several tons of prepackaged food...
每个火星开拓者同时或多或少是个农夫
every Martian pioneer is also a little bit of a farmer.
即便那样 火星上种植不是便当的
Even then, growing plants on Mars isn't as easy...
简单播下种子灌溉就行了
as simply sticking a seed in the ground and watering it.
火星的土壤 即表土是反复无常的资源
The Martian soil, or regolith, is an inconsistent resource.
即使是微量的有毒物质
Even a minute trace of toxic material...
都可以招致作物的当场死亡
can spell instant death to the crops...
给殖民地带来厄运
and doom for the colony.
他们不能依赖火星土壤来培育地球上植物
They cannot rely on Mars' soil to nurture plants from Earth.
在地球上 我们种植植物有两种不同的方法
On Earth, there are a couple of different ways that we grow plants.
我们在户外大田里种植它们
We grow them outside in the open field.
我们同时也在温室里种植它们
We also grow them in a greenhouse.
这就是地球上的温室
This is what greenhouses are like on Earth.
它们建在地面上
They're located on the surface of the ground...
利用天然的太阳辐射
they use natural solar radiation...
全年运作 没有来自太空的陨石
and they operate year-round without danger from meteorites...
和电离辐射的危险
or ionizing radiation from space.
在火星上 温室是控制作物的培育室
On Mars, the greenhouse is a controlled growth chamber...
其环境提供了植物生长所需的
an environment that provides the five cardinal factors...
五种要素
plants need for growth.
它们需要光线 需要温度
They need light, they need temperature...
需要有水 需要营养
they need water, they need nutrients...
需要大气 二氧化碳和氧气
and they need atmosphere, carbon dioxide and oxygen.
这样定居点有了培育室
So with a growth chamber in a habitat...
你就可以全年都种植粮食了
you can grow food all year round.
一般来说 它们的培育是水栽法
For the most part, they are grown hydroponically...
这个术语的字面意思是水里种植
a term that literally means "water culture."
水栽培育植物的种植无需土壤
Plants grown hydroponically are grown without soil...
是种在悬浮在水中的营养液里
in a nutrient bath suspended in water.
但是植物还是需要光线和空间来成长
But plants still need light and room to flourish...
空间是十分宝贵的
and space is at a premium.
研究人员已经将这个需求
Researchers have gotten around this requirement...
尽量解决在了一个紧凑的空间里
in the tight confines of a space far away...
利用了不起的发光二极管
by using the cool light-emitting diodes...
即LED 遮蔽光谱中的颜色
or LEDs, shaded to the colors of the spectrum...
刺激植物的生长
that stimulate plant growth.
虽然火星上的阳光适合植物
While Mars' sunshine is fine for plants...
其唯一的目的就是制造氧气
whose sole purpose is to produce oxygen...
但是此类培育室为殖民地提供了食物
these types of growth chambers provide food for the colony.
困扰移民的另一个问题
Another concern to plague the colonists--
在地球上 昆虫给植物授粉
on Earth, insects pollinate plants.
那是否意味着我们将把虫子带入太空呢?
Does that mean that we'll be taking bugs with us into space?
确实很难让蜜蜂正确导航
It's actually really difficult for bees to navigate...
因为它们利用太阳的紫外线来导航
because they use the UV light from the Sun to navigate...
它们利用很多其它的提示
and they use a lot of other cues...
我们在火星上或太空殖民地里
and we wouldn't have those same cues on Mars...
没有同样的提示
or in a space colony.
一个小发明效果神奇
A little invention works wonders.
我们有这些振动棒 其作用就如人工蜂
We have these vibrating wands that will act like artificial bees...
或利用空气流动 如风扇那样
or using air movement like a fan...
将花粉从一朵花吹向另一朵花
that's blowing the pollen around from one flower to another.
然而 我们认为
We think, though, that the astronauts ...
外星上的宇航员或移民
or the colonists of another planet...
实际上对照料植物会乐此不疲的
are actually going to really enjoy tending the plants.
不过还有在地球上种植植物的一大要素
But there's still one huge factor...
是火星上所缺失的
to growing plants on Earth that's missing on Mars...
那是技术上所无法克服的东西
and it's something that even technology can't overcome.
火星上只有八分之三的地球标准重力
It's only about three-eighths Earth's normal gravity on Mars...
因此植物所受的拉力来得较小
so there'll be less pull on the plants.
在地球上 重力将水从植物的根部排走
On Earth, gravity drains water away from the roots of plants...
让其吸入氧气
allowing them to take in oxygen.
由于重力的减弱 水就不会有效地排走
With reduced gravity, water doesn't flow efficiently...
导致浸泡根部 使其无法吸收养分和空气
leading to saturated roots, unable to absorb nutrients and air.
就有可能导致它们变弱
There'll be maybe a tendency for them to grow weaker.
究竟何种食物是我们太空农夫们所要种植的呢?
Exactly what kind of food are our space farmers growing?
土豆 生菜 寥寥无几
Potatoes and lettuce, to name just a few.
所有这些原料
Given all of these ingredients...
构成了火星典型的菜单
here's what's on the typical menu for a Martian diner.
早餐 炒鸡蛋和土豆煎饼
For breakfast, it's scrambled eggs and hash browns.
午餐是三明治
Lunch is a sandwich...
大豆或波特贝拉蘑菇制成的豆豉
tempeh made from soy or portabella mushrooms...
配上草莓
with a side of strawberries.
面食与意大利红酱作为晚餐 色拉
Pasta with marinara sauce for dinner, salad...
甜土豆饼作为甜品
and sweet potato pie for dessert.
这是严格的素食日常餐饮
This is a strictly vegetarian diet...
所以宇航员里的食肉者将倒大霉了
so the carnivores in the crew are out of luck.
即使你或许可以用各种动物来源生产出肉类
Even though you could probably produce meat...from various types of animal sources...
我有一种感觉 宇航员会对此十分嘴馋
I have a feeling the astronauts would get so attached to them...
他们不会等到它们长大就会吃掉它们的
they wouldn't want to eat them after they grew them.
保证宇航员的健康和强壮至关重要
Keeping the crew healthy and strong is essential...
因为日常工作需要超人的努力
when just a routine day's work requires a superhuman effort...
宛如获得星际大奖
like harvesting an interplanetary jackpot...
它就火星的地平线上
that lies just beyond the Martian horizon.
开展这项远征火星的长期任务的开销是个天文数字
The cost of mounting this long-term expedition to Mars is astronomical.
然而最大的回报可能超出火星
But the biggest payoff may actually be beyond Mars...
那里有个聚宝盆
where there's a cornucopia...
有极具价值的未开发资源
of extremely valuable untapped resources...
飘荡在红色星球之外
floating beyond the Red Planet.
行星地球上最大的陨石来源
The largest source of meteorites on the planet Earth...
来自小行星带
come from the asteroid belt.
我们发现其中约85%的主要成分
And we find that roughly 85 percent of them...
是硅 类似于地表
are mainly made out of silicon, similar to the surface of the Earth...
但是还有5%左右是铁
but also five percent or so have iron in them.
我们可以利用那铁来制造钢
We could use that iron in order to create steel...
来创造结构 建筑
in order to create structures and buildings and cities...
城市乃至文明
and even a civilization.
俘获小行星将稳步推进
Harvesting the asteroids smoothes the progress in assembling...
火星前哨站的建立与扩大
and expanding the Martian outpost.
构建新的设施与飞船
Constructing new facilities and spacecraft...
并且维护与更新旧的
as well as maintaining and updating the older ones...
将利用小行星带里的原矿
is accomplished utilizing the raw ores...
提炼和加工来完成
refined and processed from the belt.
并非将小行星带里的矿物带回地球
Instead of taking the minerals from the asteroid belt...
那是老命伤财
and bringing it all the way back to the Earth, that's a waste.
最好是开采小行星带
It's much better to mine the asteroid belt...
来打造火星上使用的物质
in order to create materials for Mars.
不过磨碎这些深太空石块还有另一个原因
But there's also another reason to grind up these deep space boulders.
如果你要将它们熔化 你要估计到
If you were to melt them down, you would get, it's estimated...
来自一公里大的小行星
from a one-kilometer asteroid...
整个就是全球一年的钢产量
all the world's steel production for a year...
全球十年里的金银产量
all the world's gold and silver production for ten years...
全球1000年里铂系元素的产量
all the world's platinum group element productions for 1,000 years.
因此说财富就是你的主要动机
So that's where the riches are if that's your main motivation.
一颗半英里多一点的小行星
An asteroid with a diameter of a little over half a mile...
其质量约20亿吨
would have a mass of about two billion tons.
其重量等于2万艘尼米兹级航母
That's equal in weight to 20,000 Nimitz-class aircraft carriers.
此等规模的小行星可能包含着镍 钴 铂
An asteroid of this size could contain enough nickel, cobalt, and platinum...
其价值超过1500亿美元
to be valued at over $150 billion.
这只是颗不大的小行星
And this is just a small asteroid.
有些巨石的直径达到了行星的规模
Some monster rocks approach the dimensions of a real planet.
开采小行星是史无前例的事情
Mining an asteroid is something that we've never done before.
不管怎样 或许会有办法
However, perhaps there are ways...
钻入小行星的土地
in which to dig into the asteroid's soil...
我们并不认为会有多大的难度
which we don't think is going to be that hard.
一个办法就是激光
One way is laser beams.
我们可以用高科技来产生激光
We can use high technology to create laser beams...
直接切割小行星的物质
that'll slice right through the asteroid material.
但是要在真空的太空里掏空一块巨石
But hollowing out a megaton rock in the airless void of space...
决不是一件轻而易举的任务
is by no means an easy proposition.
小行星带里的辐射相当厉害
Radiation in the asteroid belt is quite harsh...
尤其是因为
especially because Jupiter itself...
木星自身释放出大量的辐射
releases an enormous amount of radiation.
这就意味着小行星上的矿工
This means that miners on the surface of an asteroid belt...
有可能不得不生活在小行星的地下
may have to live underground inside the asteroid itself.
那会给他们一些保护
That would give them some protection...
免遭太阳的辐射
from the radiation from the Sun...
木星的辐射以及外太空的辐射
radiation from Jupiter, and radiation from outer space...
依靠生活在小行星的地下
by living inside the asteroid itself.
或许这是最好留给铁人们的活计
Maybe this is a job better left to men of iron.
因为小行星带太遥远了
Because the asteroid belt is so distant...
约有3亿英里远
perhaps 300 million miles away...
我们可能不得不用上机器人了
we may have to use robots.
机器人相对较为便宜
Robots are going to be relatively cheap...
它们无需生命的支持
they don't require life support...
它们可以有去无回
and they don't have to come back.
对于首批星际移民来说
For the first interplanetary colony...
类人机器人 与它们的宇航员伙伴一道工作
humanoid robots, working together with their astronaut partners...
是将风险降到最小 最大限度生存的唯一途径
is the only way to minimize risk and maximize survival.
火星生活的方方面面
In every way, daily life on Mars...
都将是终极冒险
will be the ultimate extreme adventure.
你早晨醒来 已经多出了一个小时的睡眠
You get up in the morning, you've had an hour extra sleep...
你会跳下床 因为只有一半的重力
you bound out of bed because there's half the gravity...
然后你穿衣外出
then you suit up to go outside...
因为你有一个小时的本职工作
because you have an hour of duty, checking on the robots...
检查维持生命的机器人
that keep life possible.
然后你掉头回家 止步在一个山坡上
And then on your way home, you stop on a ridge...
你环顾整个山谷
and you look across the valley into the canyons.
你仰望火星的天空
And you look up at the Martian sky...
繁星闪烁 蔚为壮观
with the amazing sight of stars twinkling through.
探索火星表面将会是精彩的冒险
Exploring the surface of Mars is going to be a fantastic adventure.
景观之美 无与伦比
There are landscapes that are of unimaginable beauty...
叹为观止
some completely alien to us.
无穷无尽的地貌
There are thousands and thousands of kilometers...
向四面八方延展
of terrain to cover in every direction.
那里将是科学家梦寐以求的仙境
It's going to be a fantastic wonderland for scientists.
活跃在火星殖民地上的这种景色 眼下还是幻想
This view of a working colony on Mars is, for now, fiction...
据称是21世纪的科学
informed by the best of 21st century science.
但是十有八九 有朝一日
But in all likelihood, one day...
在盘踞在外星土地上的穹顶城市里
in domed cities entrenched in alien soil...
并不是那些小绿人
rather than being little green men...
我们的天上邻居将属于我们
our celestial neighbors will be us.